SENIOR PRODUCT MANAGER

Summary

I am 41 years old, I am married, I have got 2 kids. I have just moved to US with my family on the permanent basis (have permanent residency of MA). I have huge experience both as practical doctor and in big pharma as sales, medical and marketing professional. My first specialty was clinical pharmacology. Also, I have PhD degree in cardiology and endocrinology. I have wide knowledge on all groups of drugs. I have PhD degree in cardiology and MBA degree. Having a wide experience of work both in marketing, medical and sales, as well as in a people management, I hope that I can be maximum useful for your company in achievement of the scheduled purposes. Â Skills

· Professional medical support, experienced marketer, product management

Personal Information
Date and place of birth: 12/01/1976, Yerevan, Armenia,
USA permanent residence from 2015
Married, 2 kids
Interests
MD, PhD, MBA
Professional musician,
Medicine and biotechnologies
Experience
02/2009 to 08/2017
Senior product manager Amazon.Com, Inc.

- The Operational development and execution of marketing strategies and tactics for dedicated products (Victoza and Saxenda).
- Development and execution of marketing annual plans (AMTP) Sales development, retail market and competitors constant monitoring and quick changings implementation if needed.
- Responsibility for development and execution of marketing annual budgets.
- Conduct and analyzing market research data and SoV measuring.
- Overall responsibility for pre-launch, launch and post launch for dedicated products (Victoza and Saxenda) Pricing development and
 calculation of NPV, GM, SOG for products and portfolio Development and controlling of distributors and pharmacies activities around the
 products.
- Development of communication tools and promotional materials according local laws and rules.
- Planning, organizing and executing of events and exhibitions.
- Develop and maintain scientific marketing activities including KOLs negotiation.
- Development and execution the new targeting and segmentation approaches for products.
- Involvement in recruitment, training and coaching of new KAMs and Reps.

01/2005 to 01/2008

Portfolio manager Bbcn Bank

- Worked closely with TEVA Marketing to assist in development and design of our products, towards demand generation for our existing and any new products we develop.
- Developed relevant "white papers" that highlight TEVA products value proposition; creating differentiation with competitive products.
- Evaluated TEVA products offering and suitability to our strategic market segments and channel strategies.
- Drove the products life cycle decision making for the TEVA.
- Thoroughly understand, through detailed analysis, the competitive pricing landscape so that we can set our partner's list pricing at the right levels and our own direct selling pricing levels.
- Assisted other departments/divisions as assigned by supervisor.
- Optimised TEVA products portfolio.

01/2004 to 01/2005

Cardiovascular product medical - manager medical representative IVAX Pharmaceuticals

- Lead the planning and implementation of launch plan of Simgal (simvastatin) and Felodip (felodipine) Facilitate the definition of project scope, goals and deliverables Define tasks and resource requirements Develop full scale products plans Assemble and coordinate team of medical representatives Manage budgets Manage products resource allocation plan and schedule timelines Track project deliverables using appropriate tools Singal MS in volume in statins was increased by 7% Sales was overachieved targets on 45% 2003 -2004 years.
- Berlin Chemie/ Menarini Pharma (Germany-Italy) Cardiovascular product medical manager Responsible for launching and managing the cardio products from planning to execution in support of organizational strategy and objectives.
- Successfully launch NEBILET (nebivolol) and Berlipril (generic enalapril) on the Russian market.
- Research and analyze cardio market conditions especially ACE inhibitors and beta blockers.
- Identify key competitor and patient trends Articulate market requirements and opportunities.
- Define the long term strategy of the products and create product road map Manage and communicate with cross functional teams Develop
 product marketing plan and event campaigns to generate product awareness and demand plan product launch Support sales and marketing
 with the necessary product knowledge and technical expertise Make product presentations Develop sales tools and sales training material
 Use market feedback to inform product refinements and ongoing development Sales annual plan on Nebilet was over performed on 20%
 from target MS% in volume in beta blockers was increased by 2% and became on the 3d place among all others 1999-2001 years.

- Representative office of the pharmaceutical company DHU and D-r Willmar Schwabe (Germany)The regional manager Accomplishes
 regional sales human resource objectives by recruiting, selecting, orienting, training, assigning, scheduling, coaching, counseling, and
 disciplining completely new MRs in assigned districts; Overachieved regional sales operational objectives by 20-50% in all responsible
 regions.
- Preparing and completing action plans; implementing production, productivity, quality, and customer-service standards; resolving problems; identifying trends; determining regional sales system improvements; implementing change.
- Meets regional sales financial objectives by forecasting requirements; preparing an annual budget; scheduling expenditures; analyzing variances; initiating corrective actions.
- Establishes sales objectives by creating a sales plan and quota for districts in support of national objectives.
- Maintains and expands customer base by counseling district sales representatives; building and maintaining rapport with key customers; identifying new customer opportunities.
- 1998-1999 years.
- Moscow Representative office of the pharmaceutical company DHU and D-r Willmar Schwabe (Germany) The Arranging appointments with doctors, pharmacists and hospital medical teams.
- Making presentations to doctors and pharmacists in the retail sector.
- Organizing conferences for doctors and other medical staff; Building and maintaining positive working relationships with medical staff and supporting administrative staff; Managing budgets (for catering, outside speakers, conferences, hospitality, etc.); Keeping detailed records of all contacts; Exceeding annual sales targets by 30% in dedicated districts of Moscow Regularly attending to the company meetings, technical data presentations and briefings; Keeping up to date with the latest clinical data supplied by the company, and Interpreting, presenting and discussing this data with health professionals during presentations Best Medical representative of 1999 with further promotion to Regional manager position has obtained.

Education and Training

2014

MBA Open University Business School (UK) level 1

2002

 $PhD\ Moscow\ Medical\ Academy\ year\ MMA\ in\ cardiology\ (cardiologist)\ 2001-2003\ years.\ Moscow\ Medical\ Academy.\ Department\ of\ Clinical\ pharmacology.\ The\ residency\ on\ a\ special ty\ \^{A}\ clinical\ pharmacology\ \^{A}\ >\ -\ Clinical\ pharmacologist$

Languages

Fluent English, Russian and Armenian

Activities and Honors

Achievements: I got the special recognition as the best Victoza launch executor with spot bonus awarded in 2010 I invented and implemented innovative Victoza retail Project with NEW dedicated KAMs covering retail area in 2014 I got additional funds from HQs to realize Victoza screening project, recognized as the best around IO affiliates in 2015 We have shared this experience as the best practice in IO and I participated in IO ambition film in 2015 with Victoza retail project best practice 2 Years successfully over performed annual sales plan by 20% in value. Best NEW project recognized by HQs has been developed and executed by myself Saxenda AB 2017real sales vs target YTD April 2017 is 130%.

Professional medical support, experienced marketer, product management, clinical trials, coaching, competitive, customer-service, decision making, direct selling, endocrinology, Fluent English, exhibitions, film, , financial, forecasting, functional, funds, human resource, internal medicine, managing, analyzing market, marketing plan, marketing strategies, marketing, market, MS Office, organizational, pharmacology, piano, presenting, presentations, Pricing, Develop product, promotion, promotional materials, quality, Research, retail, Sales development, sales plan, sales training, scheduling, scientific, Strategy, strategic, supervisor

Additional Information

https://www.linkedin.com/in/artem-abramian-b82024113/ Abramian Artem: MD, PhD, MBA Date and place of birth: 12/01/1976,
 Yerevan, Armenia USA permanent residence from 2015 Marital status - married, have 2 kids (9 and 11 years old) The purpose: Position in Marketing or Medical Affairs in pharma